I've done some really amazing stuff in my
30s, and buying a nice car has to be one
of the best of them.
So this video has nothing to do with what
I sell, what I'm
promoting.
It's just a little bit of advice I'd give
to someone maybe younger than
me.
There are a lot of really cool experiences
that you have in life that are
fleeting.
So you spend five grand at a beach club.
Within a month, the memory starts to fade.
Spend 10 grand on a night out getting
bottle service in Vegas, and it just blurs
into all the other nights you've had.
But when you get a car,
something you truly love,
you get to a point that you just
don't get bored of it. Now,
I'll make something clear.
I was completely fine for five years
without a car, and that's because I
had one of these things.
[skateboard scraping] Having a skateboard
is seriously cool, and if you live in a
part of a city where just having a car
just isn't going to cut it,
like I lived in
Bondi, there was no way I
was going to be having a nice car in
Bondi.
That skateboard made me so happy.
The amount of smiles
that it put on my face.
Going bus lanes through Clapham
when I lived there.
When I went to Coachella,
I took it to LA and went for a skateboard
through
Hollywood. I've taken
that around the world, and
that brings me so much
joy. Even some days,
there's nothing better than just going for
a little skate.
So I'm not saying
that everyone needs to have one of these,
because for years I was
happy with that skateboard.
But the thing is,
there comes a point in your life, and
for me, it was having a family,
that there was excitement that I
was going to lose
from other areas,
and I needed to fill the gap.
In my late 20s,
I went to Coachella with three girls I'd
never met before.
I used to do visa runs to random countries
on my own.
And I don't miss any of
that because starting a family
is the best thing I've ever
done.
But when I moved somewhere quiet down the
coast, and I spent the majority of
my time in the same location filming,
I thought I need to have a little bit of
daily excitement, and that's what this is.
I get so excited every day still.
It's been over a year.
Every day I get to drive this car,
I'm like, "Yes." Every
time I've got a meeting in the city,
"Yes." Every time my Mrs says,
"Can you go get
this from the shop?" "Yes." Now,
it doesn't have to be a Porsche.
This thing right here, it's my Golf R,
and this was to scratch an itch when I was
younger. So when I first met my partner,
she lives about an hour away, so I was
like,
"I'll get a car." This Golf R right here,
perfect.
Four-wheel drive, few hundred horsepower,
nought to 60 in five to six seconds.
Nippy. Dog could go in the back.
Practical.
The point I want to make
is for some of you,
getting a Golf R might be that thing
for excitement that you need.
And in your 30s,
where you can't really go out so
much and party and do wild shit,
I think this is probably one of the best
investments.
And I'm not talking about financial,
I'm talking about cost for
happiness.
Because we all have our earning rate,
then we have a burn rate.
So how much we spend to live,
whether it's our mortgage, costs, bills,
whatever.
There should always be an allocation for
sensible stuff like savings, but there
should also be an allocation for stuff
like having fun, and when we were younger,
we used to budget in going out,
socializing, and going for nice dinners.
I think it's a shame if you don't do
that for a car, if you're into cars
and you're
able to drive one, and you can afford one.
Now I can tell firsthand
that I've definitely been captured by the
status game
because I love the GT3 RS, which
is the model above this.
This has got a slightly bigger wing.
So I'm not sure if what I'm about to tell
you is cope or genuinely the truth.
Now, first things first, driving this car,
amazing.
Another reason you shouldn't wait too long
to get one is that getting in it is an
ordeal. So you've got to go.
I had to ask the person, "Well,
show you do this?" Put
one leg in, then you put the next leg in.
Now, six-speed manual,
absolutely the best thing in the world.
There are times in traffic I hate it,
sure.
Now the bucket seats,
at first I thought these aren't
comfortable enough.
I now love them. Roll cage,
not really needed per se.
Now, this isn't the Weissach package,
so some of the trim in here could be
carbon
fiber.
It's not really going to make much of a
difference for me.
When I saw the car, I was like,
"What weight saving am I getting from
that?" I am
not good enough at driving for
that weight saving to even matter.
GT3 RS has got a bigger wing, granted.
It's also got a little bit more
horsepower, granted.
Let me show you something it doesn't have.
Well, first thing, manual gearbox.
Second is storage for my jujitsu stuff.
"Oh, don't forget that, James.
You'll need that for Japan." In the GT3
RS, this is
just another fan. This
is great because I can fit a suitcase in
here if me and the
Mrs go away for the weekend.
So it's practical at the same time.
Now, the downforce
that I'm not going to get from this rear
wing, fair
enough. And do you know what?
I still am considering doing a little,
putting a
bigger wing on it. Not
that I need the downforce,
I just think it would look sick
as. But then another consideration hit me,
and you can tell I definitely watch too
much Matt Armstrong, because when I
was watching Matt Armstrong, I
was just seeing
a guy that loves cars just loving cars,
and I was like, "I'm a guy
that loves cars,
and I'm not loving cars."
And watching him mod cars,
watching him find
vehicles that no one would ever customize
and just having fun with it and just
riding the shit out of it,
I felt inspired by it.
Now,
he was always doing the exhaust on these
cars.
So I thought to myself, "Okay,
maybe I'll do an exhaust." Then I thought
it's a
waste of money.
But then I thought about it, right?
When you drive this, it's amazing, fun,
driving around, whatever.
But then when you drop a gear in a tunnel.
"Whoa." It makes you smile.
It makes you giggle.
It makes you go, "Oh my God, that
was so much fun." So these
are called headers.
These are the old ones that came with it.
So all of that is to capture bad emissions
and whatnot.
Now, these are the ones that I got.
Now these headers don't have catalytic
converters in. And these ones
are made out of titanium,
so they're super fucking
light. These are equal length headers,
titanium, put them in, and it sounded
amazing, but it was fucked. It
was too much.
[engine revving] That's really loud.
[engine revving]
What have we done to you? That's loud.
So when I'd start the car, the smell,
fucked, but it was too loud.
I was going to get a black flag at
racetracks, and honestly, thought I
was going to
go deaf, so I had to swap the headers.
So in there I've got a full titanium.
You can see the blue from it.
Got a full titanium exhaust in there,
which just
sounds sick as fuck.
And the reason I kind of did that,
when I was a child,
my dad used to take me to Le Mans
when I was 10, and to be 36, just having a
car that I can just mod the fuck out of,
I do it for my younger version of myself.
There is the back of the fucking exhaust.
That is all to make sure it's not too
loud.
So I was like, "Strip that out. Get
that out.
Fuck off." Put the titanium bad boy in.
But I can't tell you, right,
there's something so incredible about
being proud of
your car. So when I'm in the gym
and I'm lifting or I'm recording content,
sometimes I just stand here going,
"I can't believe that's mine." We've got
to
talk about cost. It's not cheap. And yeah,
I finance it
because it doesn't make sense to me to put
the full amount of money into a
car. Even at, I think it's 8% interest,
I could put the same amount of
cash into the flipping S&P 500, and
that would eat away a little bit of it.
Not to mention, you never know.
I'd probably rather have
that money in case someone
came up to me and go, "Hey,
I've got a really good business idea." I
could give
them 400K instead of having it sat in a
car.
And some people might think that's a silly
use, but at the end of the day, even if
you said to me, "James, the money
that you spend on finance,
you're not getting any
of it back," that's fine.
The amount of smiles this puts on my face
every time I
get in it, it's a fucking bargain.
There's also a slightly more depressing
thing to
consider. This is a 911
And the average 911 driver is 52
years old. Yeah, I saw the stat
that the average 911 driver
is 52 years old.
And I think we forget
that 16% of people aren't going to make it
to retirement.
So all of these people that
are being so strategically smart to save
all of their
money to have at the end,
some of them aren't going to make it,
nearly one in five.
And although there's financial
responsibility, these
are going to be some of the
favorite memories of my life, even
if I lose everything.
Let's say AI comes along, takes my job,
leaves me penniless.
I'll be there saying to my son, "Son,
when I was in my 30s, I had my dream car."
This isn't even my dream car,
to be honest. My dream car
was about two cars ago.
This was just the pin-up car
that I would never have dreamed of having.
And the thing is,
when you get big pay slips,
when your shares go up in value, or
you get paid for something,
you don't really feel anything.
But 9,000 RPM in a tunnel with a titanium
exhaust, oh, you feel that.
If you're watching this, maybe it's an M3,
maybe an M2, maybe an M1.
Maybe it's a Golf GTI, a Golf R,
an Audi RS3.
It's so nice to have something tangible,
so that when you've had a hard day at
work, you get in it and you're like,
"Whoa.
Yes." And out of all the financially crazy
things to do, this was the one thing
I was most scared of.
My manager pretty much said,
"Go buy the car." Every day that
my son comes home,
I put him in because he wants to.
He plays in the seats.
He presses the horn.
He puts the indicators on or whatever.
The funny thing is, when I was younger,
I never had this on my list of things to
aim for.
But as someone just potentially maybe a
little bit further ahead in the
journey than you are,
put this on your bucket list.
It's so much fun.
It's one of those things that I
was worried I would regret,
and I can't believe I
nearly didn't do it.
[car revving]
The crazy thing is,
even with a softer metal,
that's not even close to how good it
can sound. Right.
I'm taking this thing out for a rip.
Whatever it is that you're thinking about
doing, just buy it.
If you change your mind, take it back.
Think of it this way.
Let's say you're going to go get a 911
today, or insert car.
You have it for three months.
You don't absolutely love it.
You lose 10, 20,
maybe even 30 grand on it, so what?
Make 30 more.
Better to have done the thing
and to regret it than never to have
done it at all. The take-home message
is sometimes it is absolutely fantastic
to be financially irresponsible.
You're going to be dead soon.
You're going to be in the ground,
and 20 years after that,
no one will ever mention
your name again. So get as many lols,
giggles, and rips through
tunnels as you can until that day comes.
It's my best business advice I can give
you.